A Finding Aid to the Fairfield Porter Papers, 1888-2001 (bulk 1924-1975), in the Archives of American Art AAA.portfair
Archives of American Art
- Writings by Fairfield Porter, 1924-1975, undated; Series 3; (Box 2; 0.6 linear feet)
  Writings by Fairfield Porter include manuscripts and corrected typescripts of artist profiles, art criticism and theory, talks and lectures, notes, research, preparatory writings, poetry, translations, and other writings. Artist profiles include essays about Richard Stankiewicz, Joseph Cornell, and Albert York. Porter's essays on various art-related subjects are often found in multiple drafts and are filed under the title of what appears to be the latest draft. Early versions of these writings are found in Porter's research notes and other notebooks. Teaching notes include a class register and syllabus for a 1969 art course taught at Queens College in New York. Reviewing notebooks contain detailed notes and rough sketches from visits with artists made while Porter was writing criticism. Other notebooks contain a variety of entries, including prose writings and scattered poems, sketches, and other notes. Scattered notes are also found in many of the sketchbooks in th e Artwork series.
  Two folders of poetry manuscripts by Porter, and a single poem by Porter and Kenneth Koch, contain a mix of published and unpublished poems, often in multiple drafts. A few of Porter's translations from French of Stéphane Mallarmé's poetry are present in various drafts. Miscellaneous Creative Writings include a work of experimental fiction called "Lake Mahopac," a school essay entitled "A Neighbor," and a tune Porter composed for the William Blake poem "Ah, Sunflower."
  Writings in this series represent only a small portion of Porter's literary output. See Printed Materials and Anne Porter's Posthumous Projects for published writings.
  - Artist Profiles, circa 1955-1974 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Reviews, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Essays (Box 2)
    - "Art Reveals the Nature of Society", undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - "Art Should be Independent of Science", undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - "The Arts Today: Reflection of a Sick Society?", undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - "The Class Content of Modern Painting", undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - "Poets and Painters in Collaboration", undated; (First page missing) (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - "Technology and Artistic Perception", undated; (3 folders; partially scanned) (Box 2, Folder 22-24)
    - untitled, undated; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
    - Photocopied Essays, undated; (not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Talks and Lectures, 1965, 1969, 1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Notes (Box 2)
    - Paint Recipes, circa 1929-1959 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Research Notes, undated; (6 folders) (Box 2, Folder 30-35)
    - Teaching Notes, Queens College, 1969; (not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Mailing List, undated; (not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Supply Inventory, 1972-1975; (not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Notebooks (Box 2)
    - Reviewing Notebook, 1950s (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Reviewing Notebook, 1950s (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Reviewing Notebook, circa 1953 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Reviewing Notebook, circa 1954 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Reviewing Notebook, circa 1956 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Reviewing Notebook, circa 1960 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Other Notebook, circa 1931 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Other Notebooks, undated; (5 folders) (Box 2, Folder 47-51)
    - Other Notebook, circa 1975 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Poetry, undated; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 53-54)
  - Translations from Mallarmé, 1973, undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Miscellaneous Creative Writings, 1924, 1950s, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Writings by Others, 1888-1992, undated; Series 4; (Boxes 2-3; 0.7 linear feet)
  This series includes essays, diaries, poetry, notes, and other writings. Writings about Fairfield Porter include essay-length memoirs by several of his contemporaries and criticism of his writings and art written by Rackstraw Downs and others. Travel Diaries written by Porter's mother, Ruth Porter, document three family trips to Europe between 1922 and 1931. A typescript created by Anne Porter from letters she wrote to her mother between 1931 and 1960 contains passages from those letters that mention Fairfield Porter. The original letters were destroyed by Anne Porter.
  Poetry manuscripts are arranged by author, with unsigned poems at the end of the series. Included are poems in typescript and corrected typescript by some of Porter's well-known friends including John Ashbery, Robert Dash, Edwin Denby, Howard Griffin, Kenneth Koch, Carl Morse, Frank O'Hara, Larry Rivers, James Schuyler, and David Shapiro. Additional poetry manuscripts can be found in Correspondence. Published poetry is filed with Printed Materials.
  Miscellaneous essays are filed alphabetically by author with unsigned essays filed at the end of the series. These include writings of family members, including Fairfield Porter's mother, Ruth Porter, and maternal grandmother, Lucy Fairchild Furness. Also found are articles by cosmologist Arthur Young with notes by Fairfield Porter, and a review of James Schuyler's Crystal Lithium, among other writings.
  Throughout this series, photocopies are filed separately and have not been scanned.
  - About Fairfield Porter (Box 2)
    - Memoirs, 1984, undated; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 57-58)
    - Criticism, 1974-1984, undated; (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 59-61)
  - Travel Diaries by Ruth Porter, 1922, 1924, 1931; (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
  - Excerpts from Letters by Anne Porter (1931-1960), undated (Box 3, Folder 4-7)
  - Poetry by: (Box 3)
    - John Ashbery, undated; (2 folders; photocopies not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
    - Susan Baran, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Sisco E.S. Barnard, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Barbara Channing Birch, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Marc Cohen, undated; (2 folders; photocopies not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 13-14)
    - Robert Dash, 1960, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Edwin Denby, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Maggie Eaton, 1981-1983, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Margaret Tynes Fairley, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Howard Griffin, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Barbara Guest, undated; (photocopy, not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Kenneth Koch (with Janice Koch), 1955, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Jamie Levinson Morris, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Carl Morse, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Frank O'Hara, undated (Box 3, Folder 24-25)
    - Anne Porter (1954), undated; (photocopy, not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Johnny Porter, 1941-1942, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Laurence Porter, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Ruth Furness Porter, 1888, 1916, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
      (also includes short story manuscript)
    - Larry Rivers, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - James Schuyler, 1962, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - David Shapiro and Students, undated; (photocopies not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 32-33)
    - Mary Soles, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Ralph Wright, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Unknown Author 1, 1951, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Unknown Author 2, undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Unknown Author 3, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Unknown Author 4, undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Miscellaneous Unknown Authors, 1960-1961, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous Essays (Box 3)
    - by Anina Porter Fuller, 1991; (not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Lucy Fairchild Furness, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Laurence Porter, undated; (not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Leon Porter, 1989; (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 44-45)
    - Ruth Furness Porter, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Arthur Young (with notes by Fairfield Porter), 1967, undated; (partially scanned) (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Unknown Author on James Schuyler, undated (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Unknown Author, undated; (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 49-50)
  - Guest Lists, undated; (not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1964, 1982, undated; (not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Personal Business Records, 1944-1996; Series 5; (Boxes 3-4; 1 linear foot)
  Personal Business Records include account books, receipts, notes, business agreements, correspondence, bank records, inventories of artwork, appraisals, copyright registrations, and other records related to Fairfield Porter's professional activities and, to a lesser extent, personal finances. This series is arranged by type of material.
  Gallery records include contractual agreements, accounting statements of painting sales, inventories, insurance claims, and scattered correspondence. The bulk of gallery records are for Tibor de Nagy Gallery, the first to represent Porter, and Hirschl and Adler Gallery, which represented Porter from 1972 on and managed his estate after his death. Also found are records from the Brooke Alexander Gallery, which handled Porter's small oeuvre of limited edition prints.
  Inventories and appraisals include property appraisals of furnishings and other assets, as well as detailed artwork inventories created after Porter's death. Additional artwork inventories are found with gallery records for Hirschl and Adler Gallery.
  Detailed records are also found relating to the major estate gift of Porter's collection to the Parrish Art Museum (Southampton, NY), as well as smaller gifts and loans made by Anne Porter to various museums and galleries after Porter's death. These records are arranged by museum or organization name. Museum research contains notes and printed materials related to the estate settlement.
  - Account Books, 1946-1988; (8 folders) (Box 3, Folder 53-61)
  - Employment Records, 1944; (not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Funeral Expenses, 1975-1976; (not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Great Spruce Head Island Corporation Records, 1971-1977; (not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Family Trust Fund, 1980; (not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Gallery Records (Box 4)
    - Tibor de Nagy Gallery Contract and Sales Records, 1959-1972; (5 folders) (Box 4, Folder 1-5)
    - Tibor de Nagy Gallery Inventories, 1964-1969 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - M. Knoedler and Company Gallery, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Hirschl and Adler Gallery, 1972-1996, undated; (6 folders) (Box 4, Folder 8-13)
    - Brooke Alexander, Inc., 1972-1996; (4 folders) (Box 4, Folder 14-17)
    - Other Galleries and Misellaneous Receipts, 1964-1979 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Charitable Trust Records, 1986-1987; (not scanned) (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Inventories and Appraisals, 1943, 1975-1978; (4 folders including copy; copy not scanned) (Box 4, Folder 20-23)
  - Artwork Inventory Notes, circa 1976 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Parrish Art Museum Loans and Gift (Box 4)
    - Receipts and Deeds of Gift, 1976-1984 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence and Minutes, 1980-1989 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Drafts of Master List, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Press Clipping Report, 1993; (partially scanned) (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Other Loans and Gifts, 1977-1989; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 29-30)
  - Museum Research, 1982-undated; (not scanned) (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Copyrights and Permissions, 1975-1988; (not scanned) (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Anne Porter's Posthumous Projects, 1980-1988, undated; Series 6; (Box 4; 0.2 linear feet)
  This series contains research, writings, and correspondence related to three publication projects executed by Anne Porter and various editors after the death of her husband, Fairfield Porter. Projects include a catalog raisonée of Porter's artwork edited by Joan Ludman, an edition of collected letters edited by Ted Leigh, and an edition of collected poems edited by John Yau.
  Materials for the catalog raisonée include notes, correspondence, reproductions of works of art, and clippings. Correspondence contains information about the provenance and subject matter of artworks. Correspondents include John MacWhinnie, Lucian Day, Bill Berkson, and Larry Campbell. Also found is a letter concerning a forged painting, and two proposals for the catalog raisonée project.
  Materials related to the collected letters include correspondence between Anne Porter and Ted Leigh, copies of letters from a few of Porter's correspondents including James Schuyler, and a manuscript of an article by Leigh. The collected poems file contains correspondence, a typescript and a corrected proof for the 1985 publication. A copy of the Collected Poems is filed with Printed Materials. Manuscripts of Porter's poetry are filed with Writings. Publicity for these publications is filed with Printed Materials.
  - Catalog Raisonée Materials, 1980-1988, undated; (3 folders; partially scanned) (Box 4, Folder 33-35)
  - Collected Letters Materials, 1983-1988; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 36-37)
  - Collected Poems Materials, 1982-1985; (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 4, Folder 38-39)
- Printed Materials, 1934-2001, undated; Series 7; (Boxes 4-6 and 11; 1.5 linear feet; not scanned)
  Printed materials include printed artwork, books, book covers, clippings, magazines, exhibition catalogs, posters, chapbooks, journals, reproductions of works of art, and other printed miscellany primarily related to the art and writings of Fairfield Porter and others in his circle.
  Books include a book about Thomas Eakins written by Porter and a book about the New York School with an article Porter wrote about Richard Stankiewicz. Book covers illustrated by Porter are found for books of poetry by James Schuyler, Kenneth Koch, and John Koethe. Clippings include magazines, magazine clippings, newspaper clippings, and other ephemeral publications. Reviews by Porter, mostly for The Nation from 1959 to 1961, are filed separately. Artwork by Porter includes a cartoon created for the Harvard Lampoon. Articles about Porter include reviews, profiles, and obituaries.
  Exhibition catalogs and posters are present for Porter's individual and group exhibitions. A file of items found in Porter's studio at the time of his death consist mostly of photographs and illustrations clipped from newspapers and reproductions of works of art.
  Poetry publications include chapbooks, journals, and books. Volumes containing poems by the Fairfield and/or Anne Porter are filed at the beginning. Poetry publications include the magazine Poetry, Locus Solus I, two issues of Semi-Colon, four issues of John Wheelwright's Poems for Two Bits and Poems for a Dime series, which were illustrated by Porter, and James Schuyler's anthologies 49 South and Broadway 2. An issue of the journal Parenthèse with an obituary of Porter by John Bernard Myers is filed with clippings about Porter. Copies of the prints Porter made for the Wheelwright publications can be found in the Artwork series.
  Subject files include pamphlets, newsletters, and brochures related to nuclear energy, an issue with which Porter was involved, and Subud, a spiritual practice Porter followed. Printed miscellany includes a teaching guide for a slide program of Porter's paintings created by the Parrish Art Museum.
  Portions of this series have not been digitized.
  - Books, (not scanned; see also Poetry Publications) (Box 4)
    - School of New York: Some Younger Artists, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Thomas Eakins, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Book Covers with Art by Porter, 1972-1974; (not scanned; see also Poetry Publications, John Wheelwright chapbooks) (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Clippings (Box 4)
    - Reviews by Porter, 1959-1982, undated; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 43-44)
    - Artwork by Porter, circa 1927, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Articles about Porter, 1955, 1968-1976; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 46-47)
    - Articles about Porter, 1955-1990s, undated; (11 folders; photocopies not scanned) (Box 5, Folder 1-11)
    - Reviews of Anne Porter's Poetry, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings, 1967-1977, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1960-2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 14-24)
  - Exhibition Posters, 1975-1977, undated; (not scanned; see Box 11, OV) (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Items Found in Studio, 1941-1971, undated; (not scanned; see also Box 11, OV) (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Navy Blueprints, 1943; (not scanned) (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Poetry Publications, (not scanned) (Box 5)
    - Fairfield Porter's Collected Poems, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Other Fairfield Porter Publications, 1955, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Anne Channing Porter, 1934-1982; (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 30-32)
    - Anne and Fairfield Porter, 1953-1989; (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
    - John Wheelwright Chapbooks Illustrated by Fairfield Porter, 1936-1937 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Kenneth Koch and Frank O'Hara, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - John Koethe, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Katherine Porter, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Groundwater Press Chapbooks, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Subject Files, (not scanned) (Box 6)
    - Nuclear Energy, 1964-1975, undated; (5 folders) (Box 6, Folder 9-13)
    - Subud, 1957-1960; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 14-15)
  - Printed Miscellany, 1980-1990, undated; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Oversized Exhibition Posters, (see Box 5, folder 25) (Box 11 (OV))
  - Oversized Items Found in Studio, (See Box 5, folder 26) (Box 11 (OV))
- Photographs, circa 1880-1990, undated; Series 8; (Boxes 6 and 11; 0.6 linear feet)
  This series includes photographs of Fairfield Porter, his family, homes and studios, photographic studies, and works of art. Most of the photographs are unattributed, but photographs by James Schuyler, John MacWhinnie, Ellen "Pit" Auerbach, and Edith Schloss are found. Photographs of Fairfield Porter are filed at the beginning of the series, except for his childhood photographs, wedding photographs, and photographs of Porter with his wife and children, which are filed with family photographs. New York City street scenes appear to have been used as studies for some of Porter's paintings. Photographs of works of art by others include paintings by Alex Katz and Alex Haberstroh that were owned by the Porters, and a bust of Porter sculpted by Robert White. See file headings below for more information about subjects.
  Throughout this series, duplicates, negatives, and copy prints have not been scanned. The remainder of the series has been selectively scanned.
  - Fairfield Porter (Box 6)
    - Fairfield Porter, circa 1946-1972, undated; (2 folders, including copy negatives and prints) (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
    - With Siblings and Friends, circa 1931-1963, undated; (2 folders, including copy negatives and print) (Box 6, Folder 19-20)
    - In Studio, Gallery, Working, circa 1960s-1970s; (2 folders, including copies) (Box 6, Folder 21-22)
  - Family (Box 6)
    - Fairfield Porter's Parents and Their Families, 1880s-1890s, undated; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Childhood Photographs of Fairfield Porter and Family, circa 1910-1920s; (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 24-26)
    - Anne Channing Porter and Family, 1913, 1927, circa 1990 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Wedding Photographs, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Fairfield Porter, Anne Porter, and Their Children in Groups, circa 1930s-1960s; (3 folders, including negatives) (Box 6, Folder 29-31)
    - Fairfield and Anne Porter with Their Grandchildren, circa 1969, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Son Johnny, circa 1934-1977; (4 folders; not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 33-36)
    - Son Laurence, 1938-1980s; (4 folders; not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 37-40)
    - Son Jerry (Richard), 1941-1970; (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 41-42)
    - Daughter Katherine, circa 1951-1980; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Daughter Elizabeth, 1957-1985, undated; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Porter Children, Negatives, undated; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Porter Grandchildren, 1969-1989, undated; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Miscellaneous People, 1953-1954, undated; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Places (Box 6)
    - Possibly Winnetka, Illinois Home, circa 1930s (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Great Spruce Head Island, Maine, 1962-1972, undated (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Southampton, New York, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Vinalhaven, Maine, undated; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - New York City Street Scenes, 1940s-1970s; (3 folders; not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 52-54)
    - Miscellaneous Places, 1940, undated; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Works of Art (Box 6)
    - By Fairfield Porter, 1930s-1980, undated; (7 folders; not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 56-62)
    - By Others, undated; (not scanned; see also Box 11, OV) (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Oversized Photographs of Works of Art by Others, (see Box 6, folder 63) (Box 11 (OV))
- Artwork, 1918-1975, undated; Series 9; (Boxes 7-10 and 12-17; 2.2 linear feet)
  Artwork includes sketchbooks, loose sketches and drawings, illustrations, prints, and cartoons by Fairfield Porter. Artwork by others includes works of Peggy Bacon, Alex Haberstroh, Leon Hartl, and Edith Schloss, and a portrait of Porter in pencil by Joe Brainard.
  Sketchbooks contain sketches and drawings in pencil, charcoal, ink, watercolor, and pastel of subjects similar to those found in Porter's paintings: homes, family, landscapes, city street scenes, and figure studies. Notes in Anne Porter's handwriting are found in many of the sketchbooks and on sketches, and were presumably made retrospectively, upon donation of the collection. Sketchbooks also contain notes written by Fairfield Porter. Many of the dates assigned to sketchbooks in this finding aid have been estimated based on the relationship of sketches to dated paintings.
  Loose sketches and drawings are mostly from Porter's early career and schooling. Life Class Sketches are from the Art Students League and from Barbara Merrick's dance class, and include two black and white oil paintings on paper. Sketches for murals and frescoes are related to two commissioned works from the 1930s, and also include sketches in oil. A mixed group of early sketches of landscapes, people, street scenes, and copies of museum pieces, filed under the heading "miscellaneous sketches and drawings," appear to contain the pages of two disassembled travel sketchbooks, among other sketches. Sketches and drawings of people are mostly of family members, with scattered sketches of friends, neighbors, and interiors of family homes. Miscellaneous landscape sketches also include several sketches in oil. Miscellaneous painted sketches include several scenes from a trip to the Western United States in 1938, along with other landscapes, scenes, and still lifes in oil and watercolor.
  Illustrations made for the socialist arts organization Rebel Arts include a silk-screened poster and a drawing for a print made by Porter in the 1930s. Other prints found in this series are from the same era, and several of them were published in John Wheelwright's chapbooks, copies of which are filed in Printed Materials. Also among the prints is a lithograph illustrating Dostoyevsky's The Possessed, which Porter made in 1932.
  - Sketchbook, 1928-1930; (see also Box 12, OV) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Sketchbook, early 1930s (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Sketchbook, 1930s (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Sketchbooks, 1937; (2 volumes in 2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
  - Sketchbook, circa 1937 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Sketchbook, circa 1939 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Sketchbook, circa 1941 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Sketchbook, circa 1943-1944 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Sketchbook, circa 1945-1947 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Sketchbook, circa 1947 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Sketchbook, circa 1948 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Sketchbook, 1944-1948 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Sketchbook, circa 1950 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Sketchbook, circa 1952 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Sketchbook, circa 1953 (Box 7, Folder 16)